More minions. More despicable.
Despicable Me 2 is a animation, comedy, family film directed by Chris Renaud.
Gru is recruited by the Anti-Villain League to help
deal with a powerful new super criminal.
Gru (voice), played by Steve Carell.
Lucy (voice), played by Kristen Wiig.
Eduardo/El Macho (voice), played by Benjamin Bratt.
Margo (voice), played by Miranda Cosgrove.
Edith (voice), played by Dana Gaier.
Agnes (voice), played by Elsie Fisher.
Despicable Me 2 is a 2013 American animated comedy film directed by Chris
Renaud and Pierre Coffin and written by Cinco Paul and Ken Daurio.
Produced by Illumination Entertainment and distributed by Universal Pictures, it is the
second installment in the Despicable Me franchise, following the 2010 film.
The film stars the voices of Steve Carell, Kristen Wiig, Benjamin Bratt,
Miranda Cosgrove, Russell Brand, Steve Coogan, and Ken Jeong.
In the film, secret agent Lucy Wilde recruits retired supervillain Gru to investigate the theft
of a powerful mutagen by El Macho, a supervillain who pursues world domination.
Development of Despicable Me 2 began in 2010 following the success of the
original film, with the directors, producers, and writers returning.
Production was underway by February 2012, with the majority of the cast returning to voice the characters, along
with new cast members, while animation services were provided by Illumination Mac Guff in France.
Al Pacino was cast as the voice of El Macho, recording all of his dialogue, but left in May 2013 over creative differences; Bratt
was brought in to replace Pacino, and used him as an inspiration after finding imitating his voice impossible.
Heitor Pereira and Pharrell Williams returned for the sequel's music.
Despicable Me 2 premiered in Australia on June 5, 2013, and was
theatrically released in the United States on July 3.
It received generally positive reviews from critics,
who praised its humor and animation.
It earned $971 million worldwide, becoming the third-highest-grossing film of 2013
and the most profitable film for Universal Pictures at the time.
It was nominated for two awards at the 86th Academy
Awards, and received numerous other accolades.
A sequel, Despicable Me 3, was released in 2017.
The film explores themes of parent child relationship,
villain, adoptive father, secret agent, bakery.
The tone is lighthearted.